## Patrick Alcindor

Phone: (646) 787-6436 Email: p.edward.alcindor@gmail.com | GitHub: https://github.com/codystarnyc | LinkedIn: https://www.linkedin.com/in/patrick-a-a99380147/ | Portfolio: www.PatrickAlcindor.com

### **OBJECTIVES**

A creative, engaging, full stack developer with a passion for front-end development and UI Design. Specializes in customer satisfaction through teamwork and maintains a commitment to exceed expectations. Actively pursuing opportunities to provide programming skills, leadership ability, and enthusiasm to a fast-paced environment as a fullstack developer.

#### -SKILLS

### **Programming Languages and Frameworks**

JavaScript, HTML, CSS, Ruby, Sinatra, Ruby on Rails, JAVA, Spring, AJAX, ¡Query, ReactJS, Node.JS, SASS, Bootstrap, SQL, SQLite, ActiveRecord, Sqlite3, PostgreSQL, MongoDB, Git, Heroku, Adobe Photoshop, Illustrator, InDesign.

### Other Skills

Agile Project Management, Kanban, Visual Studio, TDD/BDD, RSPEC, GitHub, Travis CLI, Docker, MVC, Bower, OOP, Atom, Dependency Injection, Microsoft Office, Slack, Trello, Pivotal Tracker, AWS EC2

### Language

English, French

### PROJECTS =

### Academy Panel, Ruby on Rails

(https://patadminpanel.herokuapp.com)

- A user-friendly database panel that can effectively manage students, courses, and instructors.
- Dynamic and intuitive interface built using Bootstrap Admin templates/ Javascript and CSS.
- Technologies include Ruby on Rails, UI Branding, Data Integrity, AJAX in Rails, APIs and deploying a Rails application to

## Passion Project - Charity Auction Ruby on Rails

(https:bidsocial.herokuapp.com)

- A Charity Auction website that is dynamic and intuitive built using Bootstrap, Ruby on Rails, and CSS
- Created and sourced seeded data to create my own API and RESTful interface for auction items.
- Utilizes algorithms for bidding and countdown timer for each organization's charity auction items.

### EDUCATION=

Woz U Full stack JAVA program Phoenix, AZ

Sept 2018 - Apr 2019

A part-time 33 weeks boot camp, with an emphasis on Full-Stack JAVA Development with multiple languages and frameworks.

## New York Code and Design Academy

New York, N.Y.

Full stack Ruby on Rails program

Oct 2018 - Feb 2019

• Completed a 13 week Software Engineering Intensive program and created dynamic web applications using a variety of platforms, frameworks, and languages including: Ruby, Sinatra, Ruby on Rails

## St. John's University

Queens, N.Y.

Bachelor of Science in Pharmacy

Sep 1986 - Jan 1992

• Completed and earned a degree in Pharmacy and was licensed as a Pharmacist in New York State and Florida.

= EXPERIENCE =

### **Position**

## eDiagnostic, LLC

New York, N.Y.

Junior DevOp Engineer Feb 2019 - Present Provide strategic vision and product roadmaps for this start-up company's software platform to be utilized

by health plans, health systems, and retail channels. Dev Ops on Call for heroku/sidekiq installation

# Costco

Rego Park, N.Y.

Pharmacy Intern June 2017 – Jul 2018

- Advise customers on the selection of medication brands, medical equipment and health-care supplies and ran store management by greeting customer, transaction, inventory control, and supply management
- Consistently worked in fast paced environment with continuous wave of customers coming to store

### **Alliance for Positive Health**

Plattsburg, N.Y

Independent Contractor HIV/AIDS/STD/HCV Peer Educator

Feb 2012-Apr 2017

- Met with executive members of the Department of Corrections on a bi-weekly basis to negotiate ways in which the needs of the offender population may be met.
- Prepared and submitted monthly course outlines on how best to address the needs and concerns of offenders.